Guide to the Ralph Hodgson Papers
Yale University Library
- Siegfried Sassoon Collection, 1889-1952; Series VI.; 1.4' (3 boxes)
  - WRITINGS
    - Poetry
      - "On Scratchbury Camp," holograph, 1942 Jun 2 (Box 60, Folder 1080)
        Accompanied by another copy, entitled "On Scratchbury Hill in Wartime," holograph, same date
      - "Past and Present," holograph, 1929-32
      - "Praise Persistent," proof, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1081)
      - "Presences"
        See: "(A Vigil)", Box 60, folder 1087
      - "Presences Perfected," holograph, 1929 Dec 8
        See: Vigils, Box 60 folder 1089
      - "Resurrection," proof, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1082)
      - "Revisitation (W.H.R.R.)," holograph, 1930 Nov 29
      - "Sonnet. (Penned immediately after discovering the word 'whisker'd in Thomas Warton's 'Poems.' 1731," holograph, 1932 Dec 16 (Box 60, Folder 1083)
      - "They Were Not True," holograph, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1084)
        Working title: "Rediscoverings" With "Again the Dead..." and "Words for the Wordless"
      - "An Unfinished Prose Book," holograph, 1927 Oct 7 (Box 60, Folder 1085)
      - "An Unveiling," holograph, 1932 Dec 15 (Box 61, Folder 1086)
      - "Vibrations," holograph, n.d.
        See: "An Emblem", Box 60 folder 1064
      - "(A Vigil)," holograph, 1931 Oct 27 (Box 61, Folder 1087)
        Also published under the title "Presences" and untitled with first line of "Break silence. You have listened overlong"
      - "Vigils," holograph, 1932 Sep 22 (Box 61, Folder 1088)
      - Vigils, handmade pamphlet of twelve holograph poems (Box 61, Folder 1089)
        Contains: "December Stillness," "Presences Perfected," "Revisitation (W.H.R.R.)" "We Shall Not All Sleep," "Farewell to Youth," "Past and Present," "War Experience Footnote," "Childhood Recovered," "Credo: 1932," "Everyone Sang," "Nativity," and "[In me, past, present, future meet...]"
      - "War Experience Footnote," holograph, 1929 Apr 9
        Also published under the title "War Experience"
      - "We Shall Not All Sleep," holograph, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1090)
      - "We Shall Not All Sleep," holograph, 1929 Jun 27
      - "Wind from the Past," holograph, 1928 Oct 20 (Box 61, Folder 1091)
      - "Words for the Wordless," holograph, n.d.
        See: "They Were Not True", Box 60 folder 1084
      - "The Worst of It," holograph, 1952
        See: Box 24, folder 488
      - Editing notes in Sassoon's hand on several poems on a small slip of paper (Box 61, Folder 1092)
      - Poetry reviews, 1934-38 (Box 61, Folder 1093)
      - Press cuttings of poetry in newspapers and magazines, 1933-49, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1094)
      - Typed transcripts of nine poems, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1095)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS
    - Siegfried Sassoon, ca. 1889-[1951] (Box 61, Folder 1096-1097)
    - Siegfried Sassoon and [Stephen Tennant?], [1929-30] (Box 61, Folder 1098)
    - Hester and Siegfried Sassoon, [1934], n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1099)
    - Views of Heytesbury house and village, [1935], n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1100)
    - George and Siegfried Sassoon, [1937-49], n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1101)
      See also: Oversize, box 65, folder 1167
    - Ralph Hodgson and Siegfried Sassoon, [1938] (Box 61, Folder 1102)
    - Photographic postcards of miscellaneous places, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1103)
    - Unidentified person and place (Box 61, Folder 1104)
  - ARTWORK
    - Calling card for Hodgson designed by Sassoon (Box 61, Folder 1105)
    - Pencil drawing of a man in profile with caption "Mr. Osbert Sitwell has made up his mind to write another volume of poems", 1934 Feb (Box 61, Folder 1106)
    - Pen and ink drawing with note "Specially composed for R.H." (Box 61, Folder 1107)
  - PRINTED MATERIAL
    Clippings
    - Miscellaneous clippings about Sassoon, 1932-53
    - Other miscellaneous clippings, [1945-47?], n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1109)
    - Pamphlets
      - Royal Agricultural Benevolent Institution annual report, [1937] (Box 61, Folder 1110)
    - Postcards
      - Blank postcard, with watercolor of a pomegranate on the front, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1111)
  - OTHER PAPERS
    - "Elegies and Epitaphs by Cyprian Oyde" a blank book created by Sassoon for Hodgson, with a title page and a sentiment written and signed by Sassoon on the first page, 1924 (Box 61, Folder 1112)
    - Paper inscribed "For Ralph Hodgson From Siegfried Sassoon" originally accompanying Edward Holmes, The Life of Mozart, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1113)
    - Brown paper envelopes (empty) Sassoon's poems were sent in, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1114)
    - Wood box found containing a letter to Ralph Hodgson with small label pasted on [in Siegfried Sassoon's handwriting?] (Box 62, Folder 1115)
- Other Papers, ca. 1821-1960; Series VII.; 1.2' (3 box)
  Series VII, Other Papers, are organized into three subseries: Documents, Musical Settings of Hodgson's Poems, and Miscellaneous Papers.
  - DOCUMENTS
    - Newcastle Fire-Office. Receipts given to George Dodsworth for water, gas, and insurance, 1824 (Box 63, Folder 1116)
    - Order of the Rising Sun from the Emperor of Japan, 1938
      See: Oversize, box 67, folder 1191
    - Receipts for book purchases, 1939-60 (Box 63, Folder 1117)
    - Receipts for purchases of dogs and veterinary visits, 1919-31 (Box 63, Folder 1118)
  - MUSICAL SETTINGS OF HODGSON'S POEMS
    - Butterley, Nigel. "The Mystery," holograph, [1956]
      See: Box 31, folder 639
    - Findlayson, Alan S. "The Bells of Heaven," mimeograph
      See: Box 31, folder 647
    - Harris, Addena. "Time, You Old Gipsy Man," holograph and typescript
      See: Box 31, folder 653
    - Hoffman, Edwin Michael. "Stupidity Street," blueprint, [1944]
      See: Oversize, box 65, folder 1143
    - Milford, Robin. "The Moor" Oxford University Press, n.d.
      See: Oversize, Box 64, folder 1133
    - Spies, Claudio. "The Mystery of Eve," blueprint, 1949
      See: Box 65, folder 1144
    - Stevens, Ethel Williams. "Time, You Old Gipsy Man," holograph, n.d.
      See: Box 65, folder 1145
    - Topliffe, Carlton Veda. "Time, You Old Gipsy Man," mimeograph, [1946]
      See: Box 32, folder 684
  - MISCELLANEOUS PAPERS
    - Miscellaneous notes by Ralph Hodgson, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1119-1121)
    - Handmade dust jackets for books in Hodgson's library, made by Hodgson (Box 63, Folder 1122-1122d)
    - Handmade dust jackets for books in Hodgson's library, made by Hodgson
      - Graham, Joseph. "Equation of Payments" Geometry notebook done in calligraphy, ca. 1821 (Box 63b, Folder 1123)
      - "Leaves from the Jungle," three dried leaves, n.d. (Box 63b, Folder 1124)
      - Lipstick guard, with a note from Hodgson remarking on it, 1940 Aug (Box 63b, Folder 1125)
      - List of books in Ralph Hodgson's library, created by Beinecke Library staff, n.d. (Box 63b, Folder 1125a)
        Includes books accessioned as well as discarded by the Library
      - Lock of blond-brown hair of unidentified person, tied with a red ribbon (Box 63b, Folder 1126)
      - Notes in an unidentified hand (Box 63b, Folder 1126a)
      - Sketch of a Japanese tea house and related notes (Box 63b, Folder 1127)
      - Pipe cleaner envelope, empty, n.d. (Box 63b, Folder 1128)
      - Scrapbook containing drawings, clippings, photographs, notes, printed material, 1884-1955
        See: Oversize, box 69, folder 1210
      - Sheet music with lyrics to a Charles William Dalmon poem, "O what if the fowler my blackbird has taken..." holograph, n.d. (Box 63b, Folder 1129)
      - Sketch of a compositor's case, showing placement of letters, n.d. (Box 63b, Folder 1130)
      - Small ring binding notebook, empty, with Hodgson's address pasted inside: 286 Kings Rd Chelsea S.W. (Box 63b, Folder 1131)
- Oversize, 22.2' (11 boxes)
  Oversize contains material from Series I-IV, and VI, arranged in box order.
  - Eliot, Valerie (in Series I), 1965-74, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 1132)
  - Fan Mail (in Series I), 1922-29 (Box 64, Folder 1133)
  - Baxter, W. G. Cartoons clipped from magazines, in an album, with ms. notes by Hodgson (in Series III), 1884-88 (Box 64, Folder 1134-1138)
  - "The Bull Terrier Old New and its Origins" two folders containing clipped illustrations and prints to illustrate the history of the breed (in Series III), [1837], n.d. (Box 64, Folder 1139)
  - Fulton, A. S. (in Series I), 1951 May 25 (Box 65, Folder 1140)
  - Richards, Robert and Chris (in Series I) (Box 65, Folder 1141)
  - Wheatcroft, Christabel (in Series I), 1946 (Box 65, Folder 1142)
  - Hoffman, Edwin M. (in Series I), 1944 (Box 65, Folder 1143)
  - Spies, Claudio (in Series I), 1949 Nov 10 (Box 65, Folder 1144)
  - Stevens, Ethel Williams (in Series I), 1926 Jul (Box 65, Folder 1145)
  - Hodgson, Aurelia, ed. Tributes to Ralph Hodgson on a Hundredth Birthday September 9, 1971 Galley proofs, corrected (in Series II) (Box 65, Folder 1146)
  - Hodgson, Ralph. Ainu chief and his son, drawing in pencil (in Series III), [betw. 1927 1934] (Box 65, Folder 1147)
  - Hodgson, Ralph. Cartoons and sketches of people, twenty in pencil and pen and ink (In Series III) (Box 65, Folder 1148)
  - Hodgson, Ralph. "Tomi San (Hanamaru)" pencil and crayon drawing (in Series III), 1937 Jun 14 (Box 65, Folder 1149)
  - Hodgson, Ralph. Woman's head, possibly Dorothy Hall Smith, three drawings in pencil (in Series III), 1945, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1150)
  - Empty folders previously holding the above loose sketches (in Series III), n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1151)
  - Cook, Gordon. Two copperplate engravings of landscapes (in Series III) (Box 65, Folder 1152)
  - Rutherston, Albert. Five designs for Cymbeline. Proofs in color (in Series III), 1923 (Box 65, Folder 1153)
  - Unidentified. Japanese woodblock print, hand colored (in Series III) (Box 65, Folder 1154)
  - Unidentified. "The Strange Adventures of a Dog-Cart," disbound, illustrated short story (in Series III) (Box 65, Folder 1155)
  - Williams, Caroline. "The Towpath," etching (in Series III), n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1156)
  - Miscellaneous engravings and lithographs (in Series III), 1836-98 (Box 65, Folder 1157-1158)
  - Durham London: Kelly Co. Post Office Directory Offices (in Series IV) (Box 65, Folder 1159)
  - The Ichnography of the Cities of London and Westminster and the Borough of Southwark [London]: Engraved for the General Magazine of Arts Sciences for W. Owen at Temple Bar (in Series IV) (Box 65, Folder 1160)
  - Maps of London (in Series IV), 1833-1953, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1161-1162)
  - Northumberland. London: Kelly Co. Post Office Directory Offices (in Series IV), 1879 (Box 65, Folder 1163)
  - Clippings: Hodgson interviews (in Series V), 1959 (Box 65, Folder 1163a)
  - Miscellaneous clippings (in Series V), n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1164-1165)
  - "Copies of Old Sign Boards at the Old Curiosity Shop, Falmouth" broadside (in Series V), n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1165a)
  - Sassoon, Siegfried. "What Hope for Poetry?" Harper's Bazaar (in Series VI) (Box 65, Folder 1166)
  - George Sassoon photograph (in Series VI) (Box 65, Folder 1167)
  - "Mid 19th Century Photographs of Scottish Society" (in Series V), n.d. (Box 65a, Folder 1167a-b)
  - Hodgson, Ralph. Cartoons, fifty-nine in pen and ink and crayon, set in the 1920s and 1930s (in Series III), [1937 Feb] (Box 66, Folder 1168-1188)
  - University of Kansas City Review (in Series I), 1949-57 (Box 67, Folder 1189)
    Includes "A Flying Scroll, No. 4 and 5" galley proofs
  - Morden, Robt. Episcopatus Dunelmensis Vulgo. The Bishoprick of Durham (in Series IV), [1695] (Box 67, Folder 1190)
  - Order of the Rising Sun from the Emperor of Japan (in Series VII), 1938 (Box 67, Folder 1191)
  - McKenna, Michael. Privately issued memorial volume for McKenna, edited by Hodgson. Galleys, corrected by Hodgson, incomplete (in Series II), n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1192)
  - Sassoon, Siegfried
    - Part one, galleys, corrected (in Series VI), [1928?] (Box 68a, Folder 1193)
    - Part two, galleys, corrected (in Series VI), 1928 Jun (Box 68a, Folder 1194)
    - Part three, galleys, corrected (in Series VI), 1928 Jun (Box 68a, Folder 1195)
    - Parts four and five, galleys, corrected (in Series VI), 1928 Jun (Box 68a, Folder 1196)
    - Parts six and seven, galleys, corrected (in Series VI), 1928 Jun (Box 68a, Folder 1197)
    - Parts eight and nine, galleys, corrected (in Series VI), 1928 Jun (Box 68a, Folder 1198)
    - Part ten, galleys, corrected (in Series VI), 1928 Jun (Box 68a, Folder 1199)
    - Meredith
      - Chapters 1-3, galleys, corrected (in Series VI), [1947] (Box 68b, Folder 1200)
      - Chapters 4-10, galleys, corrected (in Series VI), [1947] (Box 68b, Folder 1201)
      - Chapters 11-14, galleys, corrected (in Series VI), [1948?] (Box 68b, Folder 1202)
      - Chapters 15-20, galleys, corrected (in Series VI), [1948?] (Box 68b, Folder 1203)
    - The Old Century
      - Chapter VI of Book II, "And Seven More Years," galleys, corrected (in Series VI), ca. 1938 (Box 68c, Folder 1204)
    - The Weald of Youth
      - Chapters 1-2, galleys, corrected (in Series VI), 1941 Oct 17 (Box 68d, Folder 1205)
      - Chapters 3-6, galleys, corrected (in Series VI), [1941?] (Box 68d, Folder 1206)
      - Chapters 7-9, galleys, corrected (in Series VI), [1942?] (Box 68d, Folder 1207)
      - Chapters 10-12, galleys, corrected (in Series VI), 1942 Mar 31 (Box 68d, Folder 1208)
      - Chapters 13-17, galleys, corrected (in Series VI), [1942] (Box 68d, Folder 1209)
  - Scrapbook containing drawings, clippings, photographs, notes, printed material, 1884-1955 (Box 69, Folder 1210)
  - Hodgson, Ralph. "Love Me, Love My Dog" two printed broadsides (in Series III), n.d. (Box bsd, Folder 1211)
  - "The Life and Death of Richard Titheridge Commonly Known in Alresford, Winchester, and Southampton as Dickey Dung Prong...." broadside (in Series IV) (Box bsd, Folder 1211a)
  - Sassoon, Siegfried. "Footnotes on the Last Fifty Years" The Saturday Book Sixth Year, galleys, corrected in an unidentified hand (in Series VI), 1946 Jun 6 (Box bsd, Folder 1212)
- Restricted Fragile Papers
  Boxes 70-72, Restricted Fragile Papers, contains fragile originals. The material is arranged in folder order and may only be seen with the permission of the appropriate curator. Preservation photocopies have been placed in the main files for reference use.
  - Box 1, folders 7, 9 (Box 70, Folder 1213)
  - Box 2, folders 30-31 (Box 70, Folder 1214)
  - Box 3, folders 37, 39, 44, 46 (Box 70, Folder 1215)
  - Box 4, folders 64, 73, 77 (Box 70, Folder 1216)
  - Box 5, folder 100 (Box 70, Folder 1217)
  - Box 6, folders 104, 116-118 (Box 70, Folder 1218)
  - Box 7, folders 126-127, 148 (Box 70, Folder 1219)
  - Box 8, folder 164 (Box 70, Folder 1220)
  - Box 9, folder 184 (Box 70, Folder 1221)
  - Box 10, folders 192-193, 198, 200, 203-204, 208 (Box 70, Folder 1222)
  - Box 11, folders 217, 231 (Box 70, Folder 1223)
  - Box 12, folder 255 (Box 70, Folder 1224)
  - Empty folder (Box 70, Folder 1225)
  - Box 13, folders 265, 267, 273 (Box 70, Folder 1226)
  - Box 14, folders 283, 287, 294 (Box 70, Folder 1227)
  - Box 15, folders 302, 311-312, 314 (Box 70, Folder 1228)
  - Box 16, folder 322, 331 (Box 70, Folder 1229)
  - Box 17, folder 347 (Box 70, Folder 1230)
  - Box 18, folder 359 (Box 70, Folder 1231)
  - Box 19, folder 379 (Box 70, Folder 1232)
  - Box 21, folder 428 (Box 70, Folder 1233)
  - Box 22, folders 436, 438-439, 442-443 (Box 70, Folder 1234)
  - Box 23, folders 446, 454, 458-461 (Box 70, Folder 1235)
  - Box 24, folders 470, 475, 486-487 (Box 70, Folder 1236)
  - Box 25, folders 500-502 (Box 70, Folder 1237)
  - Box 26, folders 514, 521-522, 528 (Box 70, Folder 1238)
  - Box 27, folders 530, 542 (Box 70, Folder 1239)
  - Box 29, folders 576-577, 593 (Box 70, Folder 1240)
  - Box 30, folders 602, 605 (Box 70, Folder 1241)
  - Box 31, folders 630, 661, 663 (Box 70, Folder 1242)
  - Box 33, folders 706-707 (Box 70, Folder 1243)
  - Box 35, folder 765 (Box 70, Folder 1244)
  - Box 36, folders 787, 796 (Box 70, Folder 1245)
  - Box 37, folders 804, 812-813 (Box 70, Folder 1246)
  - Box 38, folders 815, 817, 825, 827 (Box 70, Folder 1247)
  - Box 40, folder 842 (Box 70, Folder 1248)
  - Box 41, folder 874, 881 (Box 71, Folder 1249)
  - Box 44, folders 905-906 (Box 71, Folder 1250)
  - Box 46, folder 947 (Box 71, Folder 1251)
  - Box 55, folders 983-990 (Box 71, Folder 1252-1254)
  - Box 57, folders 991-1015 (Box 71, Folder 1255-1262)
  - Box 60, folder 1048, 1052-1053 (Box 71, Folder 1263)
  - Box 61, folders 1093-1094, 1108, 1109 (Box 71, Folder 1264-1265)
  - Box 15, folder 314 (Box 72, Folder 1266)
  - Box 19, folder 393 (Box 72, Folder 1267)
  - Box 24, folder 474, 476, 484, 486-487 (Box 72, Folder 1268)
  - Box 27, folder 536-537 (Box 72, Folder 1269)
  - Box 34, folder 744 (Box 72, Folder 1270)
  - Box 36, folder 795 (Box 72, Folder 1271)
  - Box 55, folders 983-984 (Box 72, Folder 1272-1276)
  - Box 57, folders 998, 1000, 1002-1005, 1008 (Box 72, Folder 1277)
  - Box 59, folder 1043 (Box cs, Folder 1278)